Callum Pope

Identity & Access Management Consultant

Manchester, United Kingdom 📞 +44 7773 890591 🔀 contact@callumpope.com 🛱 Full (AM, B)

in linkedin.com/in/callumpope 🔗 callumpope.com

Profile

Confident, reliable and multi-skilled consultant with a comprehensive understanding and experience in designing, developing, and deploying Identity and Access Management (IAM) infrastructure, alongside maintaining and triaging existing client infrastructure through five years of experience delivering successful identity solutions for both multinational enterprises and small-medium business solutions. Excellent crossfunctional collaborator with an ability to perform well under pressure and relate with stakeholders of all seniorities and technical ability. Curious personality with a positive mindset and a dedication to continued growth. Security cleared to a high government standard.

Professional Experience

February 2023 –

Identity Consultant

January 2024 Remote Kocho 🛮

Kocho ra

March 2019 – February 2023

Senior Identity & Access Management Specialist

Cardiff, United Kingdom

(Formerly known as Oxford Computer Group UK & ThirdSpace)

Developed and maintained identity solutions that utilised the full Microsoft Identity Stack, onboarded prospective clients with a managed service approach and particular emphasis on guiding towards cloud-centric environments. Spearheaded development of proprietary state analysis software, harmonising existing identity and mobility workloads and earning the business Microsoft Partner of the Year 2020 in Security & Compliance. Administered maintenance, modification, problem resolution and incident management. Decreased client support requests 35% YoY through setting best practice standards, creating and maintaining a consistent knowledge base and providing proactive solutions.

February 2017 – March 2019 Cwmbran, United Kingdom

Identity & Access Management Specialist

Kocho ☑

September 2016 – February 2017

CGI 17

Bridgend, United Kingdom

Interpreted and analysed business reporting requirements and communicated technical details to key non-technical stakeholders. Oversaw investigation, development, modification and testing for critical business analysis reporting solutions, utilised SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS), Power BI (PBI) and Power Automate to create penetrable and user-friendly reporting solutions, transformed

and cleansed data sources to ensure seamless data transition using extract,

transform, load methodology (ETL)

SQL Service Reporting Consultant

March 2016 – Access Management Consultant

September 2016 CGI ☑

Bridgend, United Kingdom Employed, shared and contributed to company knowledge resources, oversaw

changes, incidents and problems as direct client POC on 24-hour on-call basis and in keeping with strict service level agreements, lead internal collaboration to organize, categorize and maintain sensitive client data, assisted with onboarding

of junior colleagues in a senior capacity.

Education

January 2024 – present Computer Science (Accelerated)

Manchester, UK Lancaster University

2012 – 2015 Information Technology Extended Diploma (Level 3 WBQ)

Achieved Distinction

Ebbw Vale, United Kingdom Gwent College / Coleg Gwent ♂

2015 Computer Science

Aberystwyth, UK Aberystwyth University ☑

Certificates

(MCSE) Microsoft Certified: (I

Cybersecurity Architect Expert

Microsoft, SC-100

MICIOSOIL, SC-100

Analyzing Data with Power BI

Burning Suit

Microsoft Identity Manager

Expert

OCG Learning

(MCSA) Microsoft Certified:

Identity and Access
Administrator Associate ☑

Microsoft, SC-300

Azure AD Connect Masterclass

OCG Learning

Microsoft Identity Manager

Foundation *OCG Learning*

Privilleged Access Management (PAM) in Microsoft Identity

Manager (MIM)

Oxford Computer Training

Microsoft Identity Manager

Advanced OCG Learning

Technical Competencies

Platforms

UNIX, Linux, Windows, Mac OS, Microsoft Cloud Services (Microsoft Azure) and Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Tools & Applications

- Microsoft Identity Stack
 - Microsoft Identity Manager (MIM) and it's predecessors
 - Azure Active Directory Connect (AADC)
 - Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS)
 - Password hash synchronization, pass-through authentication & single-sign on
 - Graph API & REST API
- Enterprise Mobility & Security
 - Microsoft Intune
 - Azure Information Protection (AIP)
 - Microsoft Secure Score
 - Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics (ATP)
 - Azure Active Directory
 - Microsoft Cloud App Security (CAS)
- SoftwareIDM Identity Panel & Identity Tools
- Microsoft Exchange 2003 2019
- SQL Server 2003 2019
- SQL Server Reporting Services (inc. custom T-SQL reporting)
- PowerBI and Data Analytics
- Power Automate

Professional Projects

January 2020 – present

Security Researcher

Tesla Motors Inc.

Registered and successful 'good-faith' security researcher for Tesla, disclosing software and hardware vulnerabilities to security teams through comprehensive research reports.